All right so now we're familiar with the basics of media player in Android.
الآن نحن على دراية كافية بأساسيات مشغل الوسائط في آندرويد.
We need to take what we learned with the music player app and
ونحن بحاجة إلى أخذ ما تعلمناه مع تطبيق مشغل الموسيقى و
apply it to our Miwok App.
تطبيقه على تطبيق لغة ميوك.
But, first, we need to figure out where we should put the media player code
ولكن قبل ذلك، نحن بحاجة إلى التعرف على المكان الصحيح لوضع كود مشغل الوسائط
within our Miwok App.
في تطبيق لغة ميوك.
Now in the app demo, I showed you that when we click on a list item,
الآن في النسخة التجريبية للتطبيق، لقد وضحت لك متى ننقر فوق عنصر قائمة،
we should play the audio pronunciation for the selected word.
يجب تشغيل نطق الملف الصوتي للكلمة المحددة.
So, how do we do this programatically in the Java code?
وبالتالي، كيف نقوم بذلك الأمر على نحوٍ منهجي في كود جافا؟
Well, one way to do it is to add a click listener on to each list item.
حسنًا، هناك طريقة لفعل ذلك وهي إضافة OnClickListner في كل عنصر قائمة.
So, remember from lesson one, we defined a click listener for
تذكر ما عرضناه في الدرس الأول، لقد حددنا OnClickListener
each category view and then we implemented the OnClickListener for
لكل عرض فئة ثم بعد ذلك قمنا بتنفيذ OnClickListener
the numbers category, the family category and all the other categories.
لفئة الأعداد، وفئة العائلة وجميع الفئات الأخرى.
With that logic,
وتماشيًا مع هذا المنطق،
we could create a different OnClickListener for each list item.
بإمكاننا إنشاء OnClickListener مختلف لكل عنصر قائمة.
But if we were to have, say, a thousand words in our list,
ولكن ذلك في حالة وجود ألف كلمة في القائمة،
that would be a lot of OnClickListener objects.
في هذه الحالة سنجد الكثير من كائنات OnClickListener.
Well, of course, the android team thought that this would be a common
بالطبع، لقد فكر فريق آندرويد في أن هذا الأمر سيكون طلب عام
request, handling clicks on list items in the list view.
النقر فوق عناصر القائمة في عرض القائمة.
So they came up with the way for us as developers to easily add this behavior.
لذلك قدموا لنا هذه الطريقة كمطورين لتسهيل إضافة هذا السلوك.
To help us figure out how to do this, let's go through this exercise.
ولمساعدتنا في التعرف على طريقة فعل ذلك، هيا بنا إلى هذا التمرين.
I'd like you to research how we can define what should happen
أود منك البحث عن طريقة العثور على ما الذي يجب فعله
when a list item gets clicked on and, more specifically, what method should we
عند النقر فوق عنصر قائمة، وبالأخص، ما الوظيفة التي يجب استدعائها
call on the ListView, as well as what are the inputs to that method?
في ListView، وأيضًا ما المدخلات إلى هذه الوظيفة؟
And I'd like you to specify the data type for each input.
وأود منك أيضًا تحديد نوع البيانات لكل إدخال.
Go ahead and write your answers here.
استمر ودوِّن إجاباتك هنا.
Note that they'll be no code changes required in this exercise.
يُرجى ملاحظة أن تغييرات الأكواد غير مطلوبة في هذا التمرين.
You'll be modifying the app in the next exercise.
ستجري التعديلات على التطبيق في التمرين التالي.